Lesson 15 Secrecy in industry
工业中的秘密
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
secrecy: n.  秘密
Why is secrecy particularly important in the chemical industries?
为什么在化学工业中,保密尤其重要?
2 factors
有两个因素
effectiveness: n.  成效，效力
weigh heavily against the effectiveness of scientific research in industry.
严重地妨碍着工业中科学研究的效率:
secrecy: n.  秘密
One is the general atmosphere of secrecy in which it is carried out,
一是科研工作中普遍存在的保密气氛:
the other the lack of freedom of the individual research worker.
二是研究人员缺乏个人自由.
inquiry: n.  调查研究
In so far as any inquiry is a secret one,
任何一项研究都涉及到保密,
it naturally limits all those engaged in carrying it out
那些从事科研的人员自然受到了限制.
from effective contact with their fellow scientists
他们不能和同行们进行有效接触,
either in other countries or in universities,
不管他们是来自其他国家或其他大学,
or even,often enough, in other departments of the same firm.
甚至往往不能与本公司的其他部门的同行们进行有效的接触.
secrecy: n.  秘密
The degree of secrecy naturally varies considerably.
保密程度自然差别很大.
Some of the bigger firms are engaged in researches
某些大公司进行的研究
which are of such general and fundamental nature
属于一般和基础性的研究
that it is a positive advantage to them not to keep them secret.
因此不保密对他们才有利
process: n.  过程
Yet a great many processes depending on such research
然而,依赖这种研究的很多工艺程序
secrecy: n.  秘密
are sought for with complete secrecy
是在完全保密的情况下进行的.
patent: n.  专利；
until the stage at which patents can be taken out.
直到可以取得专利权的阶段为止.
process: n.  过程, patent: n.  专利；
Even more processes are never patented at all but kept as secret processes.
更多的工艺过程根本就不会取得专利权,而是作为秘方保存着.
This applies particularly to chemical industries,
这在化学工业方面尤其突出,
where chance discoveries play a much larger part
化学工业中偶然发现的机会要多得多,
than they do in physical and mechanical industries.
同物理和机械工业相比.
secrecy: n.  秘密
Sometimes the secrecy goes to such an extent
有时,保密竟达到了这样的程度,
that the whole nature of the research cannot be mentioned.
即连研究工作的整个性质都不准提及.
Many firms,for instance
比如,很多公司
have great difficulty in obtaining technical or scientific books from libraries
向图书馆借阅科技书籍时感到很困难,
because they are unwilling to have their names entered
因为它们不愿让人家记下它们公司的名字
as having taken out such and such a book,
和曾经借阅过某某书.
agent: n.  情报人员
for fear the agents of other firms should be able to trace the kind of research
他们生怕别的公司的情报人员据此摸到
they are likely to be undertaking.
他们可能要从事的某项科研项目.